Elder, Robert K. mss. II, 2001-2020 LMC 2967
Lilly Library
Elder, Robert K. mss. II
2001-2020
Lilly Library
Elder, Robert K.
Vetch, Aaron
LMC 2967
4 Boxes
1 folio oversize
The Elder, Robert K. mss. II, 2001-2020, consist of personal correspondence from writer and journalist Robert K. Elder to his collaborator Aaron Vetch.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2021, 2023
Arrangement
The collection consists of a single correspondence series, arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Robert K. Elder (b. 1976) is an American journalist and writer whose books include John Woo: Interviews (2005), Last Words of the Executed (2010), The Film That Changed My Life (2011), The Best Film You've Never Seen (2013), Hidden Hemingway: Inside the Ernest Hemingway Archives of Oak Park (2016), and The Doomsday Clock at 75 (2022).
Elder grew up in Montana and graduated from the University of Oregon. While in Eugene he edited the campus newspaper, The Oregon Voice, and archived the papers of Ken Kesey, housed at the university's Knight Library. Elder's work has appeared in The New York Times, The Los Angeles Times, The Boston Globe, The Oregonian, MSNBC.com, Salon.com, and many other publications. For more than a decade, he served as a staff writer at the Chicago Tribune. In 2009, Elder founded Odd Hours Media LLC, which specializes in crowdsourcing, social media, and TV production. In 2019, he became Chief Digital Officer at Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists.
Aaron Vetch is a writer and copyeditor who grew up in Montana, graduated from Concordia College, and lives in Seattle. He copyedited Last Words of the Executed (2010) and The Best Film You've Never Seen (2013). He is a coauthor with Elder and Mark Cirino of Hidden Hemingway: Inside the Ernest Hemingway Archives of Oak Park (2016).
Related Materials
See the Robert K. Elder comic book collection, 2003-2013, and the Elder, Robert K. mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of personal correspondence from Elder to Vetch, written on materials including fast food bags, magazine advertisements, CD liner notes, hotel notepads, novelty postcards and estate sale stationary, a t-shirt, a license plate, and a Whoopee cushion. Subjects include Elder's travels and his Hemingway, Moby Dick, and Elvis books; his uncertain employment; his wife Betsy and children Eva and Dylan; book, TV, and music recommendations; and in 2020, the coronavirus pandemic.
Elder, Robert K. --Correspondence.
- Correspondence
  - 2001 (Box 1)
    - Shrek screener on DVD (Box 1)
  - 2003 (Box 1)
    - Illinois license plate, February 12 (Box 1)
  - 2006 (Box 1)
    - Seurat puzzle (Box 1)
    - Monet puzzle (Box 1)
  - 2009 (Box 1)
    - Piece of foam, November 18 (Box 1)
  - 2010 (Box 3)
    - June 2023 additions (Box 3)
  - 2014 (Box 1)
    - January-June (Box 1)
    - July-December (Box 1)
    - Tiffany box, January 12 (Box 1)
    - June 2023 additions (Box 3)
  - 2015 (Box 1)
    - January-June (Box 1)
    - July-December (Box 1)
    - Edible postcard box, January 7 (Box 1)
    - T-shirt, January 25 (Box 1)
  - 2016 (Box 1)
    - January-June (Box 1)
    - July-September (Box 1)
    - October-December (Box 1)
    - Glass cube, October 1 (Box 3)
    - Karate board, November 12 (Box 1)
    - June 2023 additions (Box 3)
  - 2017 (Box 2)
    - January-May (Box 2)
    - June-August (Box 2)
    - September-December (Box 2)
    - 3D glasses, January 1 (Box 2)
    - Copper plate, May 12 (Box 2)
    - Whoopee cushion, May 21 (Box 2)
    - June 2023 additions (Box 3)
  - 2018 (Box 2)
    - January-June (Box 2)
    - September-October (Box 2)
    - November-December (Box 2)
    - Bulls sign, April 14 (Box 2)
    - Beige manifesto, May 2 (Box 2)
    - Batman v. Superman poster, October 16 (Box 2)
    - Wooden dinosaur puzzle, October 18 (Box 2)
    - Plastic skeleton card, October 29 (Box 2)
    - Hotel keycards, November 17-18 (Box 2)
    - Snowflake, November 24 (Box 2)
    - Collapsible frisbee, December 13 (Box 2)
    - June 2023 additions (Box 3)
  - 2019 (Box 2)
    - January-February (Box 2)
    - March-May (Box 2)
    - June-August (Box 2)
    - September-October (Box 2)
    - November-December (Box 3)
    - Mudhoney poster, February 7 (Ovflat 37)
  - 2020 (Box 3)
    - January-February (Box 3)
    - March (Box 3)
    - April (Box 3)
    - May-June (Box 3)
    - July-August (Box 3)
    - September-October (Box 3)
    - November-December (Box 3)
    - Boy Scouts plaque, January 26 (Box 3)
  - 2021 (Box 3)
    - January-February (Box 3)
    - March-May (Box 3)
    - June-August (Box 4)
    - September-October (Box 4)
    - November-December (Box 4)
  - 2022 (Box 4)
    - January-March (Box 4)
    - April-June (Box 4)
    - July-September (Box 4)
    - October-December (Box 4)
    - Jewel case, April 3, 2022 (Box 4)
    - Domino's box, April 10, 2022 (Box 4)